In Unity GetKey or GetButton are ways
Unity においては GetKey または GetButton 関数により
of receiving input from keys or joystick
キー入力またはジョイスティック ボタン入力を
buttons via Unity's input class.
Unity の Input クラスで処理できます。
The core differences between the two is
二つの関数の主な違いは GetKey の場合は
that GetKey specifically names keys for you
Keycode を通してキーを明示的に指定する
using key codes. For example, the Spacebar
ことです。例えば、スペースバーは
is represented by KeyCode.Space
KeyCode.Space により表現されます。
This works just fine for keyboard but it's
これはキーボードにはちょうど良いですが
recommended that you use GetButton instead
代わりに Getbutton を使用して
and specify your own controls.
自身のコントロールを指定することを推奨します。
The input manager gives you the ability to
Input Manager により、
name an input and specify a key or button for it
入力に名前をつけて、それにキーまたはボタンを指定できます。
and can be accessed by choosing
これをはトップメニューの
Edit - Project Settings - Input
Edit - Project Settings - Input により
from the top menu.
選択できます。
Then, when calling it, you can reference
そして、コールするときに、文字列を使用して
a name using a string.
その名前を参照することが出来ます。
For example, Jump.
例えば Jump の場合です。
This is a default input represented by
デフォルトでは、Jump は
the Spacebar, but we could put in a
スペースバーにより表されますが、
different key or button code in order to
別のキーまたはボタンコードを指定すれば
change the input that represents Jump.
Jump にあたる入力を変更できます。
Then when calling this button you can
そしてこのボタンをコールするとき
reference the name using the string Jump.
Jump という文字列を使用してこの名前を参照できます。
To find out what to write in to your
Positive Button に何を書くべきか
positive button check the reference in the
確認するためには、
documentation or look at the table
ドキュメントのリファレンスを確認するか
that accompanies this lesson.
このレッスンに付属する表を確認して下さい。
When using GetKey or GetButton these inputs
GetKey または GetButton を使用するとき、この入力には
have three states that return a Boolean.
3 つのステートがあり、 Boolean を戻し、
True or false. First is GetKey or GetButton.
true または false となります。最初は GetKey または GetButtonです。
This will register true or false
これにより true または false が登録され、
depending on whether the button is being pressed
いずれになるかは、ボタンが押されているか、で決まります。
or not. So currently the key is not
現時点ではキーは押されていないため、
being pressed so GetButton is returning false.
GetButton は false を戻します。
When we first press the key it then
キーを最初に押したとき、
returns true on the first frame,
最初のフレームでは true を戻して、
then as we progress through frames,
フレームを進めるにつれて、
holding down the button GetButtonDown
GetButtonDown を押したままにすると
returns to false. GetButton still equals true
false が戻されます。 GetButton は true に等しいまま
so we can check if the button is being held.
であるため、ボタンが押されているか確認できます。
Then when we release the button GetButtonUp
そして GetButtonUp ボタンを離すと
shows true, but only again on the first frame.
true が表示されますが、それは最初のフレームのみです。
As we continue, all values return to false.
続けると、後は全て値が false になります。
So let's run through that again.
それではもう一度実行してみます。
When the button is not being touched
ボタンが押されてないときは
everything is false.
全て false です。
When we first press the button we can
最初にボタンを押したか
check for this using GetButtonDown,
確認するには GetButtonDown を使用して、
which will return true. Also GetButton
これは true を戻します。さらに GetButton も
will return true. After the first frame
true を戻します。最初のフレームの後、
GetButtonDown returns to false
GetButtonDown は false を戻すので
so you can use this for tasks like
武器を一回だけ発射する、といった場合に
firing a weapon once. Then as we continue
これを活用できます。さらに続けて
to hold down only GetButton will return true.
押し続けると GetButton のみ true を戻します。
Then when we release GetButtonUp
ボタンを離したとき、 GetButtonUp が
returns true for a single frame and then
ワンフレームだけ true を戻して、それ以降は
thereafter returns back to false.
false に戻ります。
You should note that GetKey behaves
GetKey も全く同様に動作することを
exactly the same way.
覚えておくべきです。
Only that the code is written slightly differently.
唯一の違いは、コードがわずかに異なって書かれていることです。
In order to check for a button
ボタンを確認するには
we use the string of the title that was placed
Input Manager の中で
in the input manager, Jump.
Jump の 使用された名前を確認します。
But when checking for a very specific key
しかし、特定のキー入力を確認するには
we can use KeyCodes.
KeyCode を使用することが出来ます。
Because this only pertains to the exact key
これは指定されたキーのみに関連するため
it's recommended that you use GetButton
先に見てきたとおり、GetButton を使用して
and specify the inputs using the input manager
Input Manager を使用して
as shown earlier.
入力を指定することを推奨します。 (翻訳:gamesonytablet)